RESUME

Name	Scott Zhou
Birth Date	27/10/1980
Gender	Male
Nationality	Chinese
Language Skill	English: Excellent
	Chinese Mandarin: Native
	Swedish: Beginner
Telephone	+46 725398656
Email	scott.cong.zhou@gmail.com
Personal homepage	www.scottzhou.me



SUMMARY

I consider myself as an expert software designer with strong test sense. I have more than 10 years' experience in software development, which mainly focus on C and C++, and also have enough knowledge on JAVA, Python, bash, Erlang, and Ruby. I have 3 years' experience in function test with TTCN-3 and Java. I have solid knowledge of software development on Linux and Windows environment specially on server-side, experienced on network programming, data structures, IPC, multi-thread, Virtualization, cloud, cluster, scalable distributed system, database (mysql, SQL SERVER), SIP, voice Protocol (G711a u/G723/G729), RTP, ISUP. I am a good team player, with strong sense of responsibility and a good learning ability. I always been self-motivated and make things happen.

EXPERIENCE AND SKILLS

- More than 10 years software development experience and 3 years functiontest experience in telecommunication industry.
- Knowledge of Linux / UNIX / Solaris.
- Expert on C/C++ programing. Strong object-oriented design and programing skills
- Knowledge of Java, Python, bash, Erlang, Ruby.
- Have experience on KVM, Cloud, and Cluster.
- Strong test competence with TTCN-3 and be able to take the tester's point of view.
- Familiar with Ericsson IMS architecture, expert on Ericsson IMS Node MGC/MTAS.
- Familiar with Ericsson software platform (IS / TSP and CBA).
- Deep knowledge in telecommunication protocols: SIP, SIGTRAN, ISUP, H.248, SNMP, RADIUS, Diameter, RTP, etc.
- Excellent working English skills, both in oral and in written.
- Strong global cooperation experiences.

Scott Zhou

Kevingeringen 11 LGH 1101, 182 50 Danderyd | +46 72 5398 656 | scott.cong.zhou@gmail.com

EDUCATION

09/1999-07/2003 Guilin University of Electronic Technology

Bachelor - Computer Science

EXPERIENCE

09/2009-Present Ericsson AB

Software developer in CBA Core MW (Stockholm, 10/2014 -

Present)

Software developer in IMS MTAS (Stockholm, 12/2011 – 09/2014)

Software designer in IMS MGC (Shanghai, 09/2009 – 11/2011)

12/2007–08/2009 iSoftStone Information Service Corporation | Senior software

engineer, be send to working at Ericsson Shanghai branch

01/2005–12/2007 Shanghai UD Technology Co., Ltd | Software engineer

08/2003–12/2004 Shanghai NewTone Co., Ltd | Software engineer

Personal skill

- Highly motivated and committed, very energetic
- Excellent communication skills and team working spirits
- Quick learner and willing to share
- Open to take risk and try new things

PROJECT EXPERIENCE(Ericsson)

CBA Core MW Software developer (10/2014 - Present)

CBA(Component Based Architecture) is an implementation of EAG(Ericsson Architecture Guide). Core MW is a component of CBA and it implements a number of services specified by SAF (Service Availability

Forum). It is based on the third party open source product OpenSAF.

Main Responsibilities and Achievements:

- Contribute to the development of product through the software life cycle, from requirements definition through successful deployment.
- Expert on CoreMW Scaling function, adapt CoreMW to Cloud/Virtualization environment.
- Participated in CoreMW software package schema definition and deliver the implementation for Software Management module.
- Facilitated create product virtualization environment for engineer to improve develop effectiveness.
- Mentor newcomers by peer-programing, code review and technical presentation.

IMS MTAS software designer and function tester (12/2011 – 09/2014)

The Multimedia Telecommunication Application Server is an application server located on the ISC interface in an IMS network. Its purpose is to provide real time peer-to-peer communication services.

Main Responsibilities and Achievements:

- Contribute to the product development by implement new features, maintain existed functions and deliver automatic test cases.
- Work in Agile WoW and be cross-functionally.
- Participated in ST AS (SIP Trunking Application Server) responsible team, provide support towards internal and external in ST AS function area.
- Mentor newcomers.

MGC software designer (12/2007 – 11/2011)

MGC is node that provides the signaling level inter-working function between circuit switched telephone network, GSTN and packet switched multimedia networks. It is based on IS blade system.

Main Responsibilities and Achievements:

- Contribute to the product development by implement new features and maintain existed functions.
- Support issues from external customer site.
- Analysis customer requirement and write implement propose.

PROJECT EXPERIENCE (Other company)

IP Value-added Application Platform (VAP) software designer (01/2005 – 12/2007)

VAP is a VoIP development platform, providing C++ API. Based on the platform customers can be develop their own IP-based value-added application quickly and easily. VAP will block the media and SIP signaling details, the developers who use this platform can focus on the business logic. VAP use SIP as control signaling, RTP/RTCP for media transmission, and support G.723, G.729, G.711, G.726 voice protocol.

Main Responsibilities and Achievements:

- Participated in VAP software architecture definition base on the limited hardware environment.
- Implement the media handling logic base on the 3rd party RTP and codec package.
- Develop and deliver SIP base commercial applications based on VAP.

OpenSN software designer (08/2003 – 12/2004)

OpenSN a Multi Media Telecommunication Application Server with build-in Media Service. It should working together with the call control node OpenCA. It can provide following applications: prepaid card, auto attendant, voice mail, etc.

Main Responsibilities and Achievements:

 Contribute to the product development by Implement the prepaid card application, voice mail application and maintain the old functions.

Open Source EXPERIENCE

OpenSAF

CoreMW use OpenSAF to provide service availability function. Ericsson is the founder of this project and provide continually contribution to OpenSAF. I worked on implementation code and provide test on OpenSAF inside in Ericsson.

JRTPLIB

VAP (the product when I working for UD technology) use jrtplib as the RTP stack. I integrated jrtplib into VAP product.

Other personal Open Source projects

Please visit my Github homepage (https://github.com/scott-zhou) for detail informations about my personal open source project. Coding is interesting thing and I love to share my codes with the world.

- Lib-Inmdb, an in memory database which used POSIX shared memory, semaphore and provide search function with hash keyed table. (C++)
- Lib-log, asynchronous log/trace library. (C++)
- Broadcase chat server, a simple chat server implemented in Erlang.
- Top stock treading, a python script to download the top treading stock history from web and export into a csv file.
- Personal homepage, implemented in Ruby on Rails.

Training and Courses:

- Cloud Infrastructure and SDN, organized by Ericsson Academy, 3 days
- Effective JAVA, organized by Ericsson Academy, 3 days
- CBA Installation Configuration and Handling, organized by Ericsson, 3 days
- CBA Introduction, organized by Ericsson Academy, 1 day
- TSP Development, organized by Ericsson, 4 days
- IMTAF essentials, organized by Ericsson, 3 days
- TTCN-3, organized by Ericsson, 4 days
- Introduction to Lean & Agile, organized by Ericsson, 3 days